<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Meet Shah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Meet Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 08:58:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Achieve freedom by restricting yourself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/achieve-freedom-by-restricting-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/achieve-freedom-by-restricting-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s topic is controversial and it is something I have been thinking about lately. Can you achieve freedom by restricting yourself? Seems counter-intuitive, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? Let me explain.
Long back, our ancestors, the hunter gatherers, had a lot of freedom. They used to wander around in forests to collect food. They did not stay at one place for long. Then time passed by, we learned agriculture and we had to restrict ourselves to one location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My problem with hard work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-issue-with-hardwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-issue-with-hardwork/</guid>
      <description>We all have heard quotes like &amp;ldquo;you should work hard and your life will become easier&amp;rdquo; at least a million times by now. But I haven&amp;rsquo;t always found this to be helpful. Working hard is important, there is no debating that. But I have a problem with how the whole self help industry, philosophers and motivational speakers portray it, and how we feel about it. This might be a little controversial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Polarization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-polarization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-polarization/</guid>
      <description>With the election season in India over, I have a few thoughts. During this election, I observed a few things with myself as well as others. A few things about what kind of people we generally tend to follow, what kind of people influence us, why do we get influenced by the people we do.
This election was all about people being either pro Modi or anti Modi. A few people said this is a dictatorship, a few people were completely in love with Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dream you took for granted</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-dream-you-took-for-granted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-dream-you-took-for-granted/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about dreams today. Not the dreams that you see while sleeping. The dreams that keep you awake. The ones that motivate you to get out of bed and work. The ones that give you some purpose in life. We all have dreamt of something or the other. The dreams have been of different magnitudes based on the conditions around us and our age. For example, when I was in kindergarten, I used to dream that I will become the Prime Minister of India one day and all the criminals and &amp;ldquo;bad people&amp;rdquo; will run out of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The solution to most of your problems!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-solution-to-most-of-your-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-solution-to-most-of-your-problems/</guid>
      <description>In the part 5 of my blog series &amp;ldquo;The Secret to Never Ending Happiness&amp;rdquo;, I had ended by saying that most of the people don&amp;rsquo;t even know what are the factors that affect their state of mind. We can identify those factors by self evaluation or introspection. That is precisely what we are going to discuss in today&amp;rsquo;s blog. So what is introspection? I would define introspection as thinking deeply about your own thoughts, ideas and feelings and examining them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are all nepotistic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/we-are-all-nepotistic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/we-are-all-nepotistic/</guid>
      <description>Nepotism is a very hot topic for people to throw hate towards these days. But in today&amp;rsquo;s blog I will prove it to you, that knowingly or unknowingly, we all perform actions and behave in ways which are nepotistic.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the basics. What is nepotism? Nepotism is basically an unfair advantage that a person gets because he/she knows someone who can help him/her achieve something he/she wants relatively easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the part 3 of the &amp;ldquo;You are a hypocrite!&amp;rdquo; series. In part 1, we understood that every person is a hypocrite. In part 2, we got a bit of insight about the irrational and rational part of our mind. In this part, let&amp;rsquo;s explore a beautiful way of controlling your mind and using it to your own advantage.
I was reading this beautiful book recently called Energize Your Mind by Gaur Gopal Das.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the part 2 of the &amp;ldquo;You are a hypocrite!&amp;rdquo; series. In part 1, we understood that every person is a hypocrite when it comes to matters that affect their own self. Their behavior in both the cases are very different. In this part, let&amp;rsquo;s explore why that happens.
Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a scenario where you are watching the iPhone 15 advertisement and your salary is 25000 INR a month, you have just received your 1st salary and you are 22 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-1/</guid>
      <description>All humans are hypocrites; the biggest hypocrite of all is the one who claims to detest hypocrisy.
&amp;ndash; Peter Wastholm
Scene: You are in the office and you see 2 colleagues and your manager talking and laughing at something.
&amp;ldquo;What would they be talking about? Is it about me? Are they talking about the fumble I had in the presentation? OMG yes they are talking about it. Let me get closer to them so I can listen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-5/</guid>
      <description>This is the 5th part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1, part 2, part 3 and part 4 and then come back here. Now without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it straightaway.
The above diagram is a representation of everything that we have learnt in the first 4 blogs. The fp boxes represent the factors in life that affect the state of mind positively and the fn boxes represent the negatively affecting factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-4/</guid>
      <description>This is the 4th part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1, part 2 and part 3 and then come back here. Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the discussion as promised, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the the biggest pleasures you experience in life.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of arguably the biggest happiness a person experiences in their whole lifetime, the birth of their child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the 3rd part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1 and part 2 and then come back here. Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the discussion as promised, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the really small pleasures that you experience in life.
For some time, let&amp;rsquo;s forget the placebo effect and focus on the state of mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the 2nd part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1 and then come back here. At the end of part 1, we discussed about one kind of happiness, the happiness of bouncing back from all odds and we compared it to the placebo effect. We took the analogy of a depression patient in case of placebo effect and a cricketer in case of the happiness of bouncing back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-1/</guid>
      <description>Let me directly break this to you. The secret to never ending happiness can be understood by the concept of the placebo effect. Yes! You read it right. I can already hear you scream at your screen that what the hell am I talking about! How can happiness be a placebo effect. Yes, I know you have experienced happiness for real, it is not fake like the placebo effect. Just hear me out once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-4/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the story from where we had left off, if you have missed the first, second and third part, I would recommend you to first check those out and then come back here to read the part 4:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: Last time, Rajat had asked about rituals, let&amp;rsquo;s continue that discussion.
Rajat: Yes! I am fed up of my parents telling me to perform so many religious rituals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-3/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the story from where we had left off, if you have missed the first and second part, I would recommend you to first check those out and then come back here to read the part 3:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with where we had ended in the last lecture. Jimit had asked us about the fake babas and gurus.
Jimit: Yes, I am of the opinion that paap, punya, heaven and hell are misused by these babas to fool innocent people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-2/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the story from where we had left off, if you have missed the part-1, I would recommend you to first check that out and then come back here to read the part 2:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: I hope everyone remembers that we had started a debate in the last lecture, as far as I recall, Rohan had asked a question in the end which wasn&amp;rsquo;t answered because the bell rang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-1/</guid>
      <description>Whether you are on the atheist side or the theist side, you are wrong! The age old debate of science vs religion is still hot, and we all have faced it some day or another, here is my take on it in a dialogue form as a conversation between the students and teacher of a classroom:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: Let&amp;rsquo;s start the day with a prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/privacy/</guid>
      <description>privacy</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
