<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Emotions on Meet Shah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/emotions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emotions on Meet Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 08:58:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/emotions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the part 3 of the &amp;ldquo;You are a hypocrite!&amp;rdquo; series. In part 1, we understood that every person is a hypocrite. In part 2, we got a bit of insight about the irrational and rational part of our mind. In this part, let&amp;rsquo;s explore a beautiful way of controlling your mind and using it to your own advantage.
I was reading this beautiful book recently called Energize Your Mind by Gaur Gopal Das.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the part 2 of the &amp;ldquo;You are a hypocrite!&amp;rdquo; series. In part 1, we understood that every person is a hypocrite when it comes to matters that affect their own self. Their behavior in both the cases are very different. In this part, let&amp;rsquo;s explore why that happens.
Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a scenario where you are watching the iPhone 15 advertisement and your salary is 25000 INR a month, you have just received your 1st salary and you are 22 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-1/</guid>
      <description>All humans are hypocrites; the biggest hypocrite of all is the one who claims to detest hypocrisy.
&amp;ndash; Peter Wastholm
Scene: You are in the office and you see 2 colleagues and your manager talking and laughing at something.
&amp;ldquo;What would they be talking about? Is it about me? Are they talking about the fumble I had in the presentation? OMG yes they are talking about it. Let me get closer to them so I can listen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-5/</guid>
      <description>This is the 5th part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1, part 2, part 3 and part 4 and then come back here. Now without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it straightaway.
The above diagram is a representation of everything that we have learnt in the first 4 blogs. The fp boxes represent the factors in life that affect the state of mind positively and the fn boxes represent the negatively affecting factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-4/</guid>
      <description>This is the 4th part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1, part 2 and part 3 and then come back here. Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the discussion as promised, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the the biggest pleasures you experience in life.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of arguably the biggest happiness a person experiences in their whole lifetime, the birth of their child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the 3rd part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1 and part 2 and then come back here. Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the discussion as promised, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the really small pleasures that you experience in life.
For some time, let&amp;rsquo;s forget the placebo effect and focus on the state of mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the 2nd part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1 and then come back here. At the end of part 1, we discussed about one kind of happiness, the happiness of bouncing back from all odds and we compared it to the placebo effect. We took the analogy of a depression patient in case of placebo effect and a cricketer in case of the happiness of bouncing back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-1/</guid>
      <description>Let me directly break this to you. The secret to never ending happiness can be understood by the concept of the placebo effect. Yes! You read it right. I can already hear you scream at your screen that what the hell am I talking about! How can happiness be a placebo effect. Yes, I know you have experienced happiness for real, it is not fake like the placebo effect. Just hear me out once.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
