<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Meet Shah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Meet Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 08:58:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The dream you took for granted</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-dream-you-took-for-granted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-dream-you-took-for-granted/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about dreams today. Not the dreams that you see while sleeping. The dreams that keep you awake. The ones that motivate you to get out of bed and work. The ones that give you some purpose in life. We all have dreamt of something or the other. The dreams have been of different magnitudes based on the conditions around us and our age. For example, when I was in kindergarten, I used to dream that I will become the Prime Minister of India one day and all the criminals and &amp;ldquo;bad people&amp;rdquo; will run out of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-5/</guid>
      <description>This is the 5th part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1, part 2, part 3 and part 4 and then come back here. Now without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it straightaway.
The above diagram is a representation of everything that we have learnt in the first 4 blogs. The fp boxes represent the factors in life that affect the state of mind positively and the fn boxes represent the negatively affecting factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-4/</guid>
      <description>This is the 4th part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1, part 2 and part 3 and then come back here. Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the discussion as promised, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the the biggest pleasures you experience in life.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of arguably the biggest happiness a person experiences in their whole lifetime, the birth of their child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the 3rd part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1 and part 2 and then come back here. Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the discussion as promised, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the really small pleasures that you experience in life.
For some time, let&amp;rsquo;s forget the placebo effect and focus on the state of mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the 2nd part in my series, The Secret to Never Ending Happiness. If you are here for the first time, please make sure to check out the part 1 and then come back here. At the end of part 1, we discussed about one kind of happiness, the happiness of bouncing back from all odds and we compared it to the placebo effect. We took the analogy of a depression patient in case of placebo effect and a cricketer in case of the happiness of bouncing back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Never Ending Happiness - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-secret-to-never-ending-happiness-1/</guid>
      <description>Let me directly break this to you. The secret to never ending happiness can be understood by the concept of the placebo effect. Yes! You read it right. I can already hear you scream at your screen that what the hell am I talking about! How can happiness be a placebo effect. Yes, I know you have experienced happiness for real, it is not fake like the placebo effect. Just hear me out once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-4/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the story from where we had left off, if you have missed the first, second and third part, I would recommend you to first check those out and then come back here to read the part 4:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: Last time, Rajat had asked about rituals, let&amp;rsquo;s continue that discussion.
Rajat: Yes! I am fed up of my parents telling me to perform so many religious rituals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-3/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the story from where we had left off, if you have missed the first and second part, I would recommend you to first check those out and then come back here to read the part 3:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with where we had ended in the last lecture. Jimit had asked us about the fake babas and gurus.
Jimit: Yes, I am of the opinion that paap, punya, heaven and hell are misused by these babas to fool innocent people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-2/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue the story from where we had left off, if you have missed the part-1, I would recommend you to first check that out and then come back here to read the part 2:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: I hope everyone remembers that we had started a debate in the last lecture, as far as I recall, Rohan had asked a question in the end which wasn&amp;rsquo;t answered because the bell rang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are WRONG About Religion - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-wrong-about-religion-1/</guid>
      <description>Whether you are on the atheist side or the theist side, you are wrong! The age old debate of science vs religion is still hot, and we all have faced it some day or another, here is my take on it in a dialogue form as a conversation between the students and teacher of a classroom:
Teacher: Good morning students!
Students: Good morning teacher!
Teacher: Let&amp;rsquo;s start the day with a prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
