<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Observation on Meet Shah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/observation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Observation on Meet Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 08:58:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/observation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the part 3 of the &amp;ldquo;You are a hypocrite!&amp;rdquo; series. In part 1, we understood that every person is a hypocrite. In part 2, we got a bit of insight about the irrational and rational part of our mind. In this part, let&amp;rsquo;s explore a beautiful way of controlling your mind and using it to your own advantage.
I was reading this beautiful book recently called Energize Your Mind by Gaur Gopal Das.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the part 2 of the &amp;ldquo;You are a hypocrite!&amp;rdquo; series. In part 1, we understood that every person is a hypocrite when it comes to matters that affect their own self. Their behavior in both the cases are very different. In this part, let&amp;rsquo;s explore why that happens.
Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a scenario where you are watching the iPhone 15 advertisement and your salary is 25000 INR a month, you have just received your 1st salary and you are 22 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a hypocrite! - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 08:58:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-a-hypocrite-1/</guid>
      <description>All humans are hypocrites; the biggest hypocrite of all is the one who claims to detest hypocrisy.
&amp;ndash; Peter Wastholm
Scene: You are in the office and you see 2 colleagues and your manager talking and laughing at something.
&amp;ldquo;What would they be talking about? Is it about me? Are they talking about the fumble I had in the presentation? OMG yes they are talking about it. Let me get closer to them so I can listen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
